Hannah Joy Sparks

Phone: 713-542-4186 | Email: hannahjsparks@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Nursing Student in a highly ranked program, with experience in a healthcare setting. Certified Basic Life Support Provider with American Heart Association. Organized and team-oriented with proficiency in direct patient care for various populations, with an aim to improve overall health and wellness of the community.

EDUCATION / AWARDS

Bachelor of Science, Nursing 01/13/2020 - Present

 $University\ of\ Houston-Sugar\ Land$

The George Foundation Scholarship Spring, Summer 2020

Dean's List Recipient Spring 2020

o Completed: Pharmacology | Fundamentals | Pathophysiology | Mental Health |

Policy and Ethics | Nursing Research | Reading and Interpreting Scientific Literature | Leadership and Management | Perioperative Nursing | Professional Nursing Roles | Obstetrics | Nutrition

Bachelor of Science, Exercise Science 08/2014 -12/2018

University of Texas at Arlington

Dean's List Recipient – College of Nursing and Health Innovation 2017, 2018

CERTIFICATIONS

Basic Life Support Provider EpiCorps Contact Tracing

EXPERIENCE

Patient Care Assistant I | CHI St. Luke's Hospital (Med-Surg/Telemetry), Houston, TX

05/2019-01/2020

- Assess and chart vital signs of patients every 4 hours heart rate, temperature, blood pressure, oxygen
- Assess and document blood sugar for ACHS patients
- Draw the blood of each patient assigned during the shift, when ordered by the nurse
- Conduct and chart hourly rounding of patients
- Assist the patient with hygiene if needed (Perineal care, Foley/Catheter care, Bathing, and any other personal needs)

Newborn Hearing Screener | The Woman's Hospital of Texas (Mednax), Houston, TX

04/2019- 10/2019

- Conduct newborn hearing screens using the ABER test
- Educate parents about the importance of hearing screening
- Enter patient data into hospital records and hearing screen databases
- Validate hearing screens on pass/refer basis

Cardiac Rehab Intern | Texas Health Arlington Memorial Hospital, Arlington, TX

08/2018-12/2018

- Created a project about Cardiac Biomarkers and presented it to Nursing Administration
- Assessed vital signs of patients heart rate, temperature, blood pressure, oxygen
- Directed exercise routines for Phase 4 cardiac patients and monitored as they completed their exercise prescriptions
- Documented RPE, RPM/Watts, Heart Rate, and Blood Pressure (if needed) as patients exercised, while making sure they reach their MET goal by the end of their 36 visits
- Monitored ECGs of patients on Holter Monitors for any abnormalities during cardiac rehab sessions

SKILLS

Vital Signs Basic Life Support Communication

Glucose Testing Foley Administration and Care ABER Hearing Screens

Information Systems Patient Education Medication Administration

Teamwork